TODD ANDERSON

FRONT END SOFTWARE ENGINEER

http://www.custardbelly.com/blog https://github.com/bustardcelly toddanderson@taanderson.com 609.203.1005

Summary

I am an application developer with a passion for architecture, development workflows, agile practices and Test Driven Development.

Over the past 12 years, I have helped deliver web, mobile and desktop solutions with numerous companies in the enterprise and entertainment industries including Adobe, THQ, Condé Nast Publications and Motorola.

I write frequently about software and technology on my <u>blog</u> and give back to the development community by releasing Open Source Software on <u>GitHub</u>. I am also a co-author on <u>several titles</u> from O'Reilly Media and Wiley Wrox publishing.

Skills

Software Architect, Project Lead, Application Development, Test Driven Development, Agile Process, Continuous Integration, OOP, User Interface, User Experience

Languages

JavaScript HTML CSS

Flex (2, 3, 4) ActionScript (2, 3) Adobe AIR

Python Objective-C / iOS Java / Android

Experience

Infrared5

Senior Software Engineer

02 / 2008 - Present

- Project Lead and Architect on numerous user-centric and data-driven applications targeting Web, Mobile and Desktop platforms
- Architecting and developing enterprise-level applications that involve the consumption, analysis and presentation of large amounts of real-time data

for delivery, hospital and entertainment industries

- Working with executive and business on introducting and adhering to agile processes in a consultancy environment
- Establishing in-house developer operations to adhere to modern software development practices for test-driven development and continuous integration
- Instituting best-practice analysis of load and runtime performance for webbased applications

Schematic

09 / 2006 - 02 / 2008

Senior Software Developer

- Project Lead on numerous Rich Internet Applications targeting Desktop, Web and embedded systems
- Overseeing achitecture, development and resourcing of client-side applications for such clients as Condé Nast, Motorola, and Schematic
- Contributing to and defining standards and best practice guidelines to inhouse developer base
- Giving presentations on new technologies and API overviews as they relate to the Flash platform and web application development

Xplana

03 / 2004 - 09 / 2006

Sr. Actionscript Developer

- Lead developer of the company's premier product XplanaBook
- Lead client-side developer of numerous rich e-learning solutions for major publishing companies such as McGraw-Hill, Thomson, Houghton-Mifflin, etc.
- Working closely with Information Architects and Design teams to deliver compelling desktop and web-based applications
- Develop custom components for the company's products and service-based applications

Education

Rhode Island School of Design Certificate, New Media

2002 - 2003

Rhode Island School of Design BFA, Illustration

1994 - 1998

Publications

Flex 4 Cookbook O'Reilly Media

<u>Flex 3 Cookbook</u> O'Reilly Media

Adobe AIR, Create-Modify-Reuse

Wiley Wrox

Honors

- Invited Speaker, Adobe MAX 2009
- Invited Speaker, Flash And The City 2011

Interests

tdd/bdd, agile processes, application architecture, web development, the maker movement, integrated circuits, electronics, oil painting, watercolor, pen and ink, music